<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CAMES Engineering</title>
    <link>https://cames-engineering.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CAMES Engineering</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 13:00:25 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cames-engineering.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Get in touch</title>
      <link>https://cames-engineering.github.io/kontakt/getintouch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 13:00:25 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cames-engineering.github.io/kontakt/getintouch/</guid>
      <description>????</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://cames-engineering.github.io/omos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 21:05:33 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cames-engineering.github.io/omos/</guid>
      <description>???</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Caps for blood pressure monitor</title>
      <link>https://cames-engineering.github.io/posts/bloodpressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cames-engineering.github.io/posts/bloodpressure/</guid>
      <description>This project in finished and can be ordered from CAMES Engineering.
Using blood pressure monitors the cuffs can be reused. To prevent transferring bacteria between patients it is important the cuffs are cleaned. Buying the cuffs a cap is received, but the caps easily get lost. It is not possible to buy new caps from the company without buying a new cuff as well. We made caps that prevent water from entering the cuff when washing and can be made easily and in big quantities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patient specific bolus</title>
      <link>https://cames-engineering.github.io/posts/earbolus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cames-engineering.github.io/posts/earbolus/</guid>
      <description>This project is in the process of being approved by the Danish Medicines Agency. See the project at CAMES Engineering
When treating superficial cancer using radiation therapy a bolus is needed. The bolus is a tissue-equivalent material that increases the skin dose to target cancer cells better. The commercial bolus used at the hospital is flat sheets that do not fit the contours of a human ear and creates air gaps between the bolus and the ear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peripheral Venous Catheter</title>
      <link>https://cames-engineering.github.io/posts/pvc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cames-engineering.github.io/posts/pvc/</guid>
      <description>This project in finished and can be ordered from CAMES Engineering.
When performing a peripheral venous catheter (PVC), it can sometimes be difficult due to anatomical challenges. One of the solutions to this is using a ultrasound guided PVC, which is more versatile and has a higher succesrate. To learn the procedure a good training course and practical phantom is needed.
The phantom is made of ballisticgel and has three vessels, a 6 mm straight, a 3 mm straight, and a 6 mm bending vessel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wedge for gating block</title>
      <link>https://cames-engineering.github.io/posts/wedge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Nov 2016 18:25:22 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cames-engineering.github.io/posts/wedge/</guid>
      <description>This project in finished and can be ordered from CAMES Engineering.
Performing 4D scannings of the respiratory system a gating block is often used. The gating block need to be perfectly leveled for the software to detect it. Levelling the gating block is difficult on the human body (chest) since it is uneven. The wedges are expensive and often gets lost during the busy days at the hospitals. To solve this problem a wedge can be used to level the gating block.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
